<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: critical-analysis | Liu Shanyin]]></title>
  <link href="http://syliu.me/blog/categories/critical-analysis/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://syliu.me/"/>
  <updated>2017-01-03T13:57:56+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://syliu.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[syliu]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[yurnom@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Critical Analysis]]></title>
    <link href="http://syliu.me/blog/2016/12/17/critical-analysis/"/>
    <updated>2016-12-17T14:48:13+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://syliu.me/blog/2016/12/17/critical-analysis</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>n the 1980’s, designer of FC games focused much more attention on stage projecting instead of picturing or plotting. SUPER MARIO BROS was a globally popular FC game typical in this context. As for why it came out on top among all the FC games, I think there are mainly three reasons:</p>

<ul>
<li>Hidden parts</li>
</ul>


<p>All the hidden parts in SUPER MARIO BROS, like awards hidden in bricks, hidden rooms, hidden stage-breading channels and shortcuts, are exciting and haunted for the player to find, just as they are ready to find a new island.</p>

<ul>
<li>Well-designed traps and skipping platforms</li>
</ul>


<p>Skipping is the most basic operation the player can use when playing SUPER MARIO BROS. The simple operation skipping can be so attractive to the player mainly due to designing of playforms in different stages. Distance and height between every two stages are precisely calculated and repeatedly experimented. Working with various traps and platforms combined at will, movable  platforms and gears, and monstors‘ obstruction, they make up of a series of obstacles, which add to the challenges and interest in playing SUPER MARIO BROS.</p>

<ul>
<li>Highly-effective modularized stage designing</li>
</ul>


<p>There are only four main stages in SUPER MARIO BROS, which include forest, sewer, castle and underwater. However, terrain variation, monstor upgrading and time change between day and night in every stage lead to a 8-stage design. Taking the castle for instance, in its early stage there are few gears, traps and enemies, the buffering margin is high and the room for operation mistakes is large. While in the late stage, one mimor mistake will lead to the player’s beginning the game totally again and even being trapped in a maze of infinite experimenting. Despite of all these similar parts, SUPER MARIO BROS places the player under different challenges whenever he begins a new stage.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
