<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Liu Shanyin]]></title>
  <link href="http://syliu.me/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://syliu.me/"/>
  <updated>2016-12-29T16:49:47+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://syliu.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[syliu]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[yurnom@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[space]]></title>
    <link href="http://syliu.me/blog/2016/12/29/space/"/>
    <updated>2016-12-29T15:09:46+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://syliu.me/blog/2016/12/29/space</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><video id="video" controls="" preload="none" poster="http://media.w3.org/2010/05/sintel/poster.png">
  <source id="mp4" src="http://syliu.me/images/space.mp4" type="video/mp4">
</video>
这是一款利用 unreal 3 engine制作的空间解迷游戏。当我还是一名初中生时，一款名为《无限回廊》的psp游戏令我印象深刻，所以后来我也想设计一款利用空间完成解谜的游戏。</p>

<p>这款游戏的最重要的元素就是可控制移动的平台以及远距离跳板。而可移动的平台位置又受玩家视野影响，因为整个游戏是一个复杂的空间，因为结构复杂，如果没有很好地镜头引导玩家，可能会对玩家解谜造成困扰。最开始我邀请我的朋友玩我这款游戏是他们是很迷茫的，因为他们出发了机关却不知道哪里产生了变化，所以很困扰。于是我设计了大量的分镜头来提示玩家空间结构发生的变化：比如当一块平台移动会触发分镜头拉伸摄像机，这样玩家就知道是哪个地方的空间位置发生了变化。后来我再次邀请他们来玩，这次整个游戏过程流畅多了。</p>

<p>从这个游戏设计中我学到了游戏设计要注重玩家体验，玩家们不是设计师，如果没有适当的引导，他们会对游戏产生困扰，所以一款好的游戏要注重用户体验。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[α]]></title>
    <link href="http://syliu.me/blog/2016/12/29/a/"/>
    <updated>2016-12-29T15:07:12+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://syliu.me/blog/2016/12/29/a</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><video id="video" controls="" preload="none" poster="http://media.w3.org/2010/05/sintel/poster.png">
  <source id="mp4" src="http://syliu.me/images/a.mp4" type="video/mp4">
</video></p>

<p>近年许多游戏公司设计的游戏越来越复杂，游戏元素也越来越多，一个好的游戏一定要有丰富的元素支持吗？我不这么认为，我觉得即使是一个很简单的元素，只要设计出彩，一样能做成好游戏。所以我设计了一款2D AVG 游戏《α》。</p>

<p>这款游戏最基础的几个操作就是上下左右，跳跃，发射子弹，以及最关键的空间传送。围绕着空间传送这个功能我设计了很多障碍，比如子弹能够穿过人却无法穿过的墙壁，只有使用空间传送才能穿过这些墙壁，而且这些墙壁有两种状态，彩虹状态时子弹也是无法穿透的。空间传送也是有限制的，它最远只能达到九个单位距离，利用这一特性我设计了会规律移动的平台，再配合各种机关解迷，使整个游戏过程充满乐趣。</p>

<p>设计这个游戏的过程中我学会了如何利用游戏本身来引导玩家，以及如何利用分镜头来引导玩家。还有如何通过关卡设计来掌控游戏节奏使完全全程都觉得这个游戏很有意思。最重要的是，我学到了原来把简单做到极致也是一种成功。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[PERSONAL STATEMENT]]></title>
    <link href="http://syliu.me/blog/2016/12/19/personal-statement/"/>
    <updated>2016-12-19T17:27:41+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://syliu.me/blog/2016/12/19/personal-statement</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Is it game or it is art? I keep pondering over this question while playing, or should I say enjoying, the superb game, Journey. As I marvel at the imaginative storyline, majestic graphics and magnificent music, I cannot help but wonder when I would design a game equally amazing. However, in China, many people hold prejudice towards game design due to lack of knowledge of this field. Worse still, game design in China is underdeveloped and the techniques are in dire need of updating. Growing up, I have been heavily influenced by classic games such as Last of Us and Uncharted by Naughty Dog. To me, games are a visual art with deep and diverse attributes, where visuals, music, narrative, gamers’ experience and realism of the game all carry a big weight. My eternal enthusiasm for game design propelled me to embark on a career in this industry, and further, contribute my part to promote the development of game design in China.</p>

<p>As much as I love game design and aspire to gain systematical body of theories and techniques, there were not many options for students who aim to major in game design. During four years of undergraduate study in E-commerce, the curriculum primarily enabled me to set up a robust foundation of computer knowledge and skills. Courses like Network Programming Language, C Language, Commerce Websites and System Design and Development, etc. familiarized me with C++, Java, SQL, ERP, and Photoshop. All of these facilitated my practices in the field of game design. Besides, courses like Internet Marketing also helped me form a comprehensive understanding of Internet marketing, which will benefit me when I deal with promotion of games in the future. In this respect, my graduation project “Analysis on the Predicament of Want Want China’s Internet Marketing Strategies and Countermeasures” further deepened my comprehension of marketing. Expanding channel of distribution, raising product’s added value and optimizing market prices were the recommendations I put forward in the paper. I believe marketing strategies will aid me greatly as promotion is a vital link in game design; and this is especially true in China.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>It was during my internships that I gained a real understanding of game play through firsthand engagement in the projects. Initially, my understanding of game play was just drawing pictures coupled with programming. The internships taught me that game is closely related to life. It takes a wide range of expertise and profound insights to design a perfect game. For instance, script and narrative skills are necessary for the plot design; cinematic techniques are required if there are animations; as for music, a designer should possess knowledge of songwriting. During my first internship at GA Game &amp; Education, I for the first time participated in a series of activities related to game design. Not only did I develop useful skills, but also made friends of similar ideals and beliefs. It was then that I realized that cooperation and team work were just as essential as skills. Only when all members of the same team maintain good communications, can the project stay on the right track. This rewarding experience reinforced my resolution to devote my life to game design.</p>

<p>In 2015, I interned at Epic Games where I was highly involved in the designing process of four key projects, namely Ash’s Wars, Titan’s Heart, α，and Water Margin Heroes. During this process, I achieved unprecedentedly rapid growth as I tried my hand at every type of work in game design. For Ash’s Wars and Titan’s Heart, I was mainly responsible for the planning of copywriting and game system, which made me realize the importance of scheming in game design. The setup of the world, chronicles, and forces as well as the design of scenes, characters, numerical system and system tasks took a lot of efforts, deliberation and creativity. As I established the key elements in the game, I think I also built a world of curiosity and great appeal. Working in teams of seven and five, I also trained my teamwork ability and communicative skills. Later, under the instruction of Cheng Xue at Epic Games, I used Unreal Engine 3 to develop a 2d AVG game, in which players control a robot that can transmit a messenger. The flight distance of the messenger is three game units. Revolving around this element, a large amount of game scenes was designed, and thereby I designed many NPC enemies to control the pace of the game. In Water Margin Heroes, I took on the role of the Numerical Game Designer. Under the instruction of Zhang Heng from Ubisoft China Shanghai branch, I designed a MOBA games based on 108 Water Margin heroes. To balance the entire game, I referred to many classic MOBA games and designed the skills of the ten martial generals from the perspectives of effects, range and harm of skills. Throughout the whole process, I gradually became more experienced in terms of techniques, and gained a thorough understanding of the overall procedure as well as nuanced details of game design.</p>

<p>Internship at Epic Games granted me knowledge and insights into this field. At the same time, it also exposed my weaknesses. Since I have not been professionally trained before, I took many game design courses such as Internet Game Design, Mobile Game Design, Basics of Programming, Basics of Fine Art, Game Development, etc. All of those courses infused me with all the knowledge I need to know and opened my eyes to the real game design industry. During my time there, I also participated in the 2015 ChinaJoy Gaming Exhibition at B2B section with our game Global Mission.</p>

<p>My internship at Beijing FingerSky Internet Tech Company Limited elevated me on a different level. I fully engaged in nearly all the essential links in the design of the demo of VR game The Adventures of Three Tomb Raiders for 2016 ChinaJoy Gaming Exhibition. I firstly set up the battle procedures for the demo, when I determined that there would be four battles and set up a specific number of monsters and the entire battle field. According to the original novels, I designed the monsters, conducted scene optimization, compiled the rules for random map generation, designed modules of core scenes, made sound effects and ran debug. Further, I touched upon the economic side of game design. On the basis of the mind map of the game design offered by our lead designer, I determined the economic source, established the economic model and drew the economic output consumption curve according to the life cycle of the games. Lastly, I also analyzed the factors affecting the VR experience, frame rate, latency, and resolution. My opinion was that we could only solve these issues through the game design instead of hardware. To avoid dizziness, we should give gamers self-controlled angle of view and eliminate dizziness-triggering scenes. With guidance from professionals and top-notched designers in this industry, I now have adopted the mindset of game designers and equipped myself with sufficient skills to aid me in breaking into this endlessly intriguing industry.</p>

<p>My internships undoubtedly improved my professional competence. In college, I also actively participated in a set of extracurricular activities which were in one way or another related to game design. For instance, I engaged in the stage design of night gala and gave full play to my edge of aesthetics and creative power. Besides, I am passionate to join in the big force of volunteers. Aside from volunteering in activities such as anniversary of the founding of our college, I particularly enjoyed visiting children with autism. Trying to build a connection with them was largely like building a world in a game. When the world is not yet built, the designing part can be extremely hard. However, the satisfaction brought by the end product is beyond words. I was glad I had brought joy to those children. In return, this experience also inspired me to design games for autistic children. Game can be a therapeutic outlet for dealing with our unique problems. It would be the upmost achievement if I can someday design a game for people with special needs.</p>

<p>The infinite charm of game design will forever fascinates me and so I would love to devote my whole life to this industry. I consider myself a man of a strong will. Though I did not have the opportunity to major in game design in my undergraduate study, I have been preparing for my graduate study since junior year by learning about computer and drawing. I plan to gain a more systematic understanding of this discipline and the United States is without a doubt the holy ground for this purpose. After careful research, I chose New York University as my ideal choice. With the guidance from your experienced faculty, flexible curriculum, and powerful network of alumni, I believe I can receive the best education there is in this field, and even step on the threshold of my career. By setting the ambition of becoming a competent game designer, I plan to acquire more in-depth knowledge and interact actively with professors and industry tycoons in my graduate study. After graduation, it is my plan to embark on my career as a planner in one of the big companies like Blizzard. In the long term, I aspire to become a producer and lead a team to design large scale console games exactly as I envision them to be. After accumulating enough experience, I will bring the new techniques and concepts back to China, realizing my self-value by contributing my own part in the development of game design.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Art Works]]></title>
    <link href="http://syliu.me/blog/2016/12/18/my-art-works/"/>
    <updated>2016-12-18T08:57:05+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://syliu.me/blog/2016/12/18/my-art-works</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://syliu.me/images/1.jpg"></p>

<hr />

<p><img class="center" src="http://syliu.me/images/2.jpg"></p>

<hr />

<p><img class="center" src="http://syliu.me/images/3.jpg"></p>

<hr />

<p><img class="center" src="http://syliu.me/images/4.jpg"></p>

<hr />

<p><img class="center" src="http://syliu.me/images/5.jpg"></p>

<hr />

<p><img class="center" src="http://syliu.me/images/6.jpg"></p>

<hr />

<p><img class="center" src="http://syliu.me/images/7.jpg"></p>

<hr />

<p><img class="center" src="http://syliu.me/images/8.jpg"></p>

<hr />

<p><img class="center" src="http://syliu.me/images/9.jpg"></p>

<hr />

<p><img class="center" src="http://syliu.me/images/bg.jpg"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[超级马里奥兄弟游戏中三点出彩的设计]]></title>
    <link href="http://syliu.me/blog/2016/12/17/chao-ji-ma-li-ao-xiong-di-you-xi-zhong-san-dian-chu-cai-de-she-ji/"/>
    <updated>2016-12-17T14:48:13+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://syliu.me/blog/2016/12/17/chao-ji-ma-li-ao-xiong-di-you-xi-zhong-san-dian-chu-cai-de-she-ji</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>超级马里奥兄弟游戏中三点出彩的设计</h2>

<p>上世纪80年代，游戏不以画面甚至剧情取胜，更注重的是关卡设计，这也让制作者们把更多精力投入其中。《超级马里奥兄弟》（《SUPER MARIO BROS.》）就是在这样的背景下诞生的一款风靡全球的游戏。为什么超级马里奥兄弟能从那么多fc游戏中脱引而出，我认为以下三点起了很大作用。</p>

<ul>
<li>隐藏要素</li>
</ul>


<p>超级马里奥兄弟隐藏在砖头中的奖励，隐藏的房间，隐藏的跳关管道，以及各种捷径，但玩家发现隐藏的要素就像发现新大陆一样令人激动。</p>

<ul>
<li>精确设计的陷阱及跳跃平台</li>
</ul>


<p>超级马里奥兄弟中玩家能用的最基本的操作就是跳跃，一个简单的跳跃如何能吸引玩家，这就涉及到关卡中平台的设计，每一个平台之间的距离和高度都是经过精确计算和反复尝试的，配合不断组合的各种陷阱平台、可移动平台、机关、怪物干扰形成一系列障碍，从而增加了游戏的挑战性和趣味性。</p>

<ul>
<li>高效的模块化关卡设计</li>
</ul>


<p>在超级马里奥兄弟中，主要的基本场景只有森林、下水道、城堡、水下四种。但是每种场景通过里面的地形变换，怪物升级，甚至还有天气变换（白天和黑夜）硬是完成了八大关卡的设计。以城堡为例，初期的城堡内部只有少量的机关陷阱和敌人，并且缓冲余地高，操作容错率也比较大。而到了游戏后期，一不小心就要重头来过，甚至还有可以无限循环的迷宫。这些虽然都是相似的元素，但玩家每进行一个新的关卡时都会面临不一样的挑战。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
