<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: design-statement | Liu Shanyin]]></title>
  <link href="http://syliu.me/blog/categories/design-statement/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://syliu.me/"/>
  <updated>2017-01-03T13:57:56+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://syliu.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[syliu]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[yurnom@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[space]]></title>
    <link href="http://syliu.me/blog/2016/12/29/space/"/>
    <updated>2016-12-29T15:09:46+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://syliu.me/blog/2016/12/29/space</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><video id="video" controls="" preload="none" poster="http://media.w3.org/2010/05/sintel/poster.png">
  <source id="mp4" src="http://syliu.me/images/space.mp4" type="video/mp4">
</video></p>

<p>It is a game of solving space puzzles via unreal 3 engines. As a middle school student, I was so deeply impressed by a PSP game called Echochrome that I managed to design via space a puzzle-solving game called SPACE.</p>

<p>The most important part of SPACE is its controllably moving stages and long-distance gangplank. Because the game was placed in a complicated space, the specific position of moving stages is affected by the player’s eye shot. With its complicated structuring, the game always perplexes the player unguided by a good lens. In the beginning, my friends felt rather perplexed in playing the game, because they did not know where changes came from after starting the gear. Thus, I devised many sub-lens to hint the player about changes on space structuring. For example, when a stage is moved, a sub-lens will be triggered to stretch the camera so that the player knows where the space structuring is changing. This has made the whole game process much easier and smoother.</p>

<p>In designing the game SPACE, I have realized that players’ more than designers’ experience should be focused in designing games. Otherwise, players will be perplexed. Therefore, in designing a good game, players’ experience should never be over-emphasized.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[α]]></title>
    <link href="http://syliu.me/blog/2016/12/29/a/"/>
    <updated>2016-12-29T15:07:12+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://syliu.me/blog/2016/12/29/a</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><video id="video" controls="" preload="none" poster="http://media.w3.org/2010/05/sintel/poster.png">
  <source id="mp4" src="http://syliu.me/images/a.mp4" type="video/mp4">
</video></p>

<p>Although computer games designed by companies are becoming more and more complicated and increasing in their game parts, a good game does not necessarily need to have abundant game parts. In my opinion, as long as it is uniquely designed, a simple game can be listed as GOOD. With this perspective, I have managed to design a 2D AVG game called α.</p>

<p>The most basic operations in playing α are moving up and down, left and right, skipping, emitting bullets and space transmission which is the most importance operation. Focused on space transmissions I have designed many obstacles such as walls which can be passed through by bullets. A man can pass through these walls only if he resorts to space transmission. There walls have two forms and during their rainbow form, even bullets cannot pass through. And, space transmission is limited because it can only reach as far as 9 distance units. Under this circumstance, I have designed a regularly-movable platform, which works with various gear puzzles to increase the fun in playing α .</p>

<p>During the process of game designing, I have learnt to lead the player via the game itself as well as the story board. Besides, I have managed to make the whole game-playing process funny and interesting by controlling the game rhythm with stage plans. Most of all, I have realized that it has turned out a great success to polish a simple thing to its utmost.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
